Cristhian López Zambrano

(+593) 990-901765 thianlopezz@gmail.com in/thianlopezz thianlopezz.com

I am a JavaScript full-stack web developer with +7 years of work experience developing mobile and web applications. I began my developer career in the fintech field with Microsoft technologies such as .Net framework and its ecosystem. I have experience as an entrepreneur delivering mobile, web apps, and integration software processes for personal clients, also in the education field as an instructor teaching JavaScript technologies. For the last years, I have worked in the e-commerce industry with technologies such as WordPress, WooCommerce, and Flutter, also developing fintech with ReactJs and PHP Laravel.

EXPERIENCE

Jobsity - Parallel Public Works, Full Stack Developer — Ene 2022- Present

- Revamped product architecture, accelerating Gatsby-based static file generation for large web pages, resulting in a 60% reduction in build time.
- Optimized development workflows by implementing DevContainers/Docker, achieving an 80% reduction in setup time for development environments.
- Implemented AuthO integration for seamless authentication within the company's tech ecosystem, linking the decoupled Gatsby frontend to the Drupal backend.
- Successfully migrated legacy data to new Drupal-based content sites, seamlessly incorporating built-in plugins for enhanced functionality.
- Develop client's requirements for web content and web app, pages with Gatsby and Drupal.

Consejo de Gobierno del Régimen Especial de Galápagos, System Information Analyst — Jul 2021- Dic 2021

- Managed public procurement and contracting processes
- Developed robust and scalable web applications using ReactJs, PHP Laravel, and Docker
- Managed institutional software applications like electronic billing systems, among others
- Configured SSL certificates
- Managed database and application servers

Liris SA, Mobile application Analyst —May 2021-Jul 2021

• Enhanced and sustained advanced features within Ionic V3 framework for two pivotal mobile applications under company ownership. Successfully contributed to the evolution of a dedicated internal application tailored for employee use, as well as an expansive E-commerce App serving a user base exceeding 14,000.

JSS TECHNOLOGIES, Full Stack Developer —Jan 2021- May 2021

• Engineered a client-specific Fintech Web sales app with advanced form processing, integrated video calls, and end-to-end automation of prospecting, contract generation, digital signing, and reporting.

Bitbox, Systems integrator —May 2020-Jan 2021

- Developed a microsite using Laravel and Tailwind CSS that had to support +50k clients, allowing users to check if applicable to get digital coupons.
- Built a WordPress plugin with PHP logic to synchronize WooCommerce entities (products, orders, categories, tags, etc) capable of being reused to integrate whichever client wants to implement an eCommerce website. This plugin is working on 3 client shops (Juan Marcet, Disensa, Veris).
- Programmed a self-checkout solution for an assurance company, automating the sale of insurance policies using lonic Framework and the WooCommerce API. Its automation released the operational work for the car revision process.

Ecudevs, Founder, teacher, developer, marketer— SEP 2018-APR 2020

• Designed a software solution based on PHP Laravel to automate educational program planning tracing and developed a web app for making lessons and evaluating students using MEARN Stack technology.

- Developed 3 learning programs and dictate classes of "JavaSript from Zero to Hero", "Desarrollo de web apps con Angular", "Desarrollo de web apps con React" and "Desarrollo de apps Híbridas con Ionic Framework".
- Redesigned a client app for Android and IOs for employees clocking using React Native with Expo and Redux, delivering a well-designed UX and robust clocking solution using the camera and Google Maps.
- Product owner of Nomadem, a web and mobile application that connects travelers to local agencies in the Galapagos Islands.

Sipecom, Semi senior .Net programmer — ENE 2016-JUN 2017

- Maintained a complete transactional web application for clients' providers where they can manage product orders using AngularJS and ASP.NET and C#.
- Built a process using C# for generating account statements and performing a process to send email notifications to 500k + clients of the biggest Ecuadorian bank.
- Developed and shipped an application to control employees' travel expenses, using jQuery and ASP.NET MVC, this application reduced 30% of the time for beginning the expenses process return.

Fondo de Cesantía del Magisterio Ecuatoriano, Junior .Net programmer — OCT 2014-MAR 2015

Developed and maintained web applications using C# and Asp.Net.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: JavaScript, NodeJs, PHP, C#, Dart

Frameworks and Tools: ReactJs, Angular 2+, Expo, Flutter, MySQL, MongoDB, Nginx, Docker, AWS, Google Firebase

Languages: English, advance; Spanish, Native.

EDUCATION

Universidad Católica de Santiago de Guayaquil – Guayaquil, Ecuador *Bachelor of Science, Systems Engineering, Oct 2018*